( rousing orchestral fanfare playing )
( fanfare ends )
( suspenseful music playing )
( child squealing in distance )
( quiet , haunting theme playing )
( birds chirping , wings flapping )
( laughing )
( both laughing )
( screams )
WOMAN : Ready to go faster ?
GIRL : All right . No , no , no !
You 're gonna slide off .
Oh !
You all right ?
- Are you sliding ? - Yes .
No , if you 're sliding , I 'm going to stop .
- No , no , no . - You okay ? Okay .
( both laughing )
WOMAN : More ?
GIRL ( giggling ) : Yes !
( screaming )
( pills rattle in bottle )
( sighs )
That 's funny .
I could 've sworn I saw a little girl
by the name of Emily come in here .
( singsongy ) : Come out , come out ,
wherever you are ...
Could she be hiding in the closet ?
( playful gasp )
I wonder where she could be .
Hmm ...
Maybe my eyes have deceived me .
I 'm invisible , Mommy .
Well , if you 're invisible ...
( laughs )
... then how could I ... do this ? !
( both laughing )
( screams )
Did you know where I was ?
Not a clue .
You want Alex ?
What is it ?
I love you more than anything else in the world .
You know that , don 't you ?
I love you , too .
( kisses )
( whispering ) : Good night , sweetheart .
Make the face .
( giggling ) : Please .
( both laughing )
- Now , go to sleep . - Okay .
( light switch clicks )
Mommy !
Sorry .
Good night .
( footsteps departing )
You coming to bed ?
In a little while .
Something you want to talk about ?
( sighs )
Some things are beyond therapy , David .
( faucet dripping )
( sighing slowly )
( cheering )
( soft click )
( faucet dripping slowly )
( dripping continues )
Honey ?
( indistinct conversation )
( sighs )
I should 've seen it coming .
All the signs were there .
The ones closest to you are the hardest to judge .
No , but I ...
I could 've prevented it .
David , it 's not your fault .
How long have we known each other ?
Trust me when I tell you this .
As difficult as it may seem , you 're ...
you 're gonna have to try and start over .
We 're gonna move .
Upstate .
The country .
That 's not exactly what I meant by " starting over . "
What about Emily ?
This is a traumatic time for her .
I think it 's important she stays here and works through this .
No , here , she 's flooded with memories .
I need to expose her to a new environment ,
new things to do ...
She 'd be losing another person she depends on .
It 's only an hour away .
And ... you 're always welcome to come and see her .
And right now , I need to do what 's right for Emily .
I need to be a full-time dad .
I have a surprise for you .
( simple , sweet " Mockingbird " melody playing )
When I was your age , my mom gave me one just like that .
And whenever I was feeling sad ,
I would open the lid , and all my sorrows went away .
Do you like it ?
( melody continues )
Give me a hug .
( melody ends )
You 're going to like it there .
All right , let 's go .
( engine starting )
( haunting melody begins )
# # CHILD ( vocalizing )
( bird cawing )
# # ( vocalizing continues )
# # ( vocalizing ends )
( orchestra continues theme )
( theme fades into wind whistling )
( tires crackle over gravel )
DAVID : Come on .
Let 's take a look .
MAN : Right on time .
Dr. Callaway ...
Mr. Haskins .
Hello .
This is Sheriff Hafferty .
Sheriff .
He routinely checks on the houses up here
to make sure things run smoothly .
I see . Well , this is
my daughter , Emily . This is Sheriff Hafferty .
Emily .
How are you ?
This is Mr. Haskins .
He found us the house .
Well , hello there , Emily .
Think your dad did a good job picking the house ?
She 's still deciding .
Well , she sure is pretty .
Thank you .
HASKINS : As I mentioned ,
Woodland Estates is mainly
a summer community .
May be a little quiet up here till then .
Hope that 's not a problem .
- Not at all . - Great .
Let me show you around the back .
HAFFERTY : You ever spent
much time in the country ?
Not much .
I used to camp when I was little ,
but I was always scared of the woods .
( chuckles )
Nothing to be scared of in these woods .
Picked a nice spot .
Biggest house on the lake .
Sheriff , if you 'd like to do the honors ;
let Dr. Callaway into his new home .
Figure out which key ...
Did you see where my daughter went ?
Emily !
Honey ?
You okay ?
Come on . Let 's go back .
Come on .
( urging ) : Come on .
Mr. Haskins , Sheriff ... we 'll take it from here .
( owl hooting )
Spaghetti and meatballs is your favorite dish .
You 're not hungry ?
I 'd like to go to bed now .
I 'll come up and kiss you good night .
( owl hoots outside )
( music box plays " Mockingbird " softly )
Oh , that 's funny .
I could have sworn I saw a little girl
by the name of Emily come in here .
I wonder ...
where she 's hiding .
Could she be ... could she be ...
under the bed ? !
No .
Could she be ...
hiding ...
Let 's see , where could she be hiding ?
Could she be hiding in the ... closet !
( cat screeching )
( music box continues playing )
Okay ...
since it 's the first night in a new house ,
I thought it would be a good time to start a new diary .
Each day you can write down
your feelings and thoughts ,
and then , one day , you can look back
and see how much they 've changed .
Hmm ?
I love you more than anything else in the world , sweetheart .
You know that .
That 's what Mommy said .
Hmm ?
Before she killed herself .
Sweetheart , she meant what she said .
And so do I.
You want me to put this
over here ?
Okay .
All right .
Good night .
( whispering ) : Good night , Alex .
( door creaking )
( plastic rustling )
( rustling )
( bird screeching )
( leaves crunching )
( music playing faintly through headphones )
( music playing faintly )
Emily ? Emily !
Em ?
Emily ?
Oh , there you are .
Come on , sweetheart .
We 're going into town . We have some errands to do .
Oh ...
Hello .
Hi ... Hi , there .
I-I 'm Laura . I live next door .
Oh , I 'm David . How are you ?
Uh , here . These are for you .
Oh , thank you very much .
My husband and I made the preserves ourselves .
Oh , well ...
I didn 't even realize anyone else lived up here .
Well , it does get pretty quiet in the off season .
Oh , this is my daughter , Emily .
Emily , say hello to Laura .
She 's our neighbor .
Isn 't she adorable ?
You going to say hi ?
Well , she gets a little shy
around new faces .
I understand .
It 's going to be a real treat having both of you here .
Oh , you 're on your way out .
I won 't keep you .
Um , if you need anything , don 't hesitate to stop by .
Same here .
And thank you for all the preserves .
The peach and apricot preserves .
- Enjoy . - Thank you .
I 'm gonna put this inside .
( wheels clacking )
( whistle blows )
WOMAN : Amy , don 't swing so high .
I 'm going to tell your mom .
Would you listen to me ?
( geese squawking )
( swing squeaking )
Hi .
I have , uh , a daughter the same age .
She 's in the car .
Oh .
I 'm Elizabeth .
Elizabeth Young .
Hi . David Callaway .
- How are you ? - Good .
Nice to meet you .
Are you visiting ?
Just moved up from the city .
Oh , usually it 's the other way around .
I know .
She your kid ?
Oh , no . No .
She 's my sister 's kid .
I 'm the honorary baby-sitter .
Watch .
Amy , be careful .
Amy ...
( shrieks )
Oh ...
- Amy . - She all right ?
Amy , Jesus , are you all right ?
( laughing )
That 's very funny .
Oh , my God , you 're going to make me nuts ,
you know that ?
Is your daughter this crazy ?
Where 's Alex ?
I don 't like her anymore .
Did I just hear what I think I heard ?
Are you mad , Daddy ?
No , I 'm not mad at all , honey .
I think it 's great .
You do ?
Yeah .
Good .
Because I have a new friend .
A new friend ? Okay .
Let me guess . Is it , um ...
Veronica ?
No .
Uh , is it , uh , Patty ?
Is it ...
He 's not a doll .
He 's ...
Not a doll .
He .
Okay , well ,
if he 's not a doll , then who is he ?
He doesn 't want me to talk about him .
Doesn 't want you to talk about him ?
( whispers ) : No .
Well , what if I promise
to keep it a secret , could you tell me then ?
So , what 's his name ?
He told me to call him Charlie .
Charlie ? Oh , that 's an interesting name .
Charlie .
When did you meet Charlie ?
Today .
When we went to town ?
It was before that .
Before that . Huh .
Is he ... here right now ?
I think he 's sleeping .
Okay .
Well , in that case ,
we better not wake him , hmm ?
KATHERINE : It 's not unusual
for a traumatized child to create imaginary friends .
I know , I just wish she 'd confide in me
instead of using fantasy .
Trauma causes pain .
Eventually the mind will find a way to release it .
No kidding .
Don 't forget : I 'm the one who taught you that stuff .
As a matter of fact , you did , yes .
Just have fun with her , David .
Play with her .
That 's what she needs .
( chain rattling )
( raindrops pattering )
CLERK : These are beginner rods .
( sports broadcast plays indistinctly )
Let 's see ... two rods ,
$ 41.50 each ...
( clerk mumbling )
Plus bait and tackle ...
Sheriff .
You parked in a handicap zone .
Oh , I didn 't even realize .
Could you give me a break ? I didn 't realize .
Enjoy your day .
Eh , so much for
small town hospitality , honey .
- Shut the door . - We broke the law .
I know we broke the law .
Shut the door .
DAVID : The Loch Ness Monster .
EMILY : What ?
You know what that is ?
It 's in Scotland .
This is a good spot , huh ?
( grunts softly )
Honey , what are you doing ?
( inhales quietly )
You think that 's a good idea ?
Emily , we have bait .
See ?
All right .
Did you have a nice time today ?
It was okay .
Just okay ?
Mm ...
Well , then , what could we have done to make it better ?
What if Charlie was there ?
Would he have made it better ?
He 's a lot of fun .
Fun like how ?
Fun like Mommy .
It 's a little stuffy in here .
( pounding on frame )
( straining )
It 's stuck .
It 's okay , Daddy .
It just ...
( squeaking , wind whistling )
( slow , regular breathing )
CROWD ( fading in ) : ... three , two , one ...
Happy New Year !
( slam echoing )
( distorted cheering )
( steady breathing )
( soft click )
( faucet dripping )
( steady breathing )
( dripping continues )
( door creaks )
( light switch clicks )
( dripping continues )
Emily , why would you do this ?
I didn 't do it .
What do you mean , you didn 't do it ?
There 's nobody here but us .
It wasn 't me .
This is your writing , and these are your crayons , honey .
It 's all right . Just tell me .
You don 't have to lie to me .
I 'm not lying .
Okay , well , if you didn 't do it ,
then who did ?
It was Charlie .
DAVID : She thinks I 'm responsible
for Alison 's death .
KATHERINE : It 's Charlie that holds you responsible .
Use him , David .
Use him to get through to her .
He 's the key .
I-I have to go , I ...
I think I found her a real friend .
Really ? That 's great .
Call me if you need me , okay ?
- Bye . - Okay , bye .
Hi .
- Hi . - Hi .
Hi , Amy .
Glad you came .
Em ... we have guests .
Emily ?
This is Elizabeth .
Hi , Emily .
Emily , this is Amy .
Hi .
Coffee-maker has a mind of its own .
( chuckling ) : Oh , God ...
Thank you .
So , is that your wife ?
She passed away .
I 'm sorry .
No matter how many times I say it , it still sounds so strange .
Must be hard on Emily .
Have you ever been married ?
Actually , I just got divorced .
I 'm living with my sister
and her husband till I can figure out my next move .
Best way to get over the past is to start something new .
That 's why we 're here .
( rhythmic thudding in distance )
AMY ( sing-song ) : ... baby , wrap it up
in toilet paper , put it in the incubator .
What shall it be ?
Oh ! By the way , this is Penelope .
Thanks .
You 're gonna like it here .
It 's a lot of fun .
Well , it 's not always fun ,
but there are lots of fun things to do .
( whispers ) : Oh ...
She 's beautiful .
What 's her name ?
Well , you don 't talk much , do you ?
You shouldn 't be here .
Why not ?
You could get hurt .
( door thudding )
- Oh , my God . - Okay .
So , um ... so , you have my number .
I 'll talk to you soon .
Okay ...
I guess I should go .
- Yeah . - Okay .
- Bye . - Bye .
Bye , Emily .
So ... what 'd you think of Amy ?
Did you like her ?
I don 't need any more friends .
( bird cawing in distance )
MAN : Good , good .
There .
Perfect .
Hi .
Hey . Sorry .
I didn 't mean to intrude .
Oh , uh ...
I 'm Steven .
Laura 's husband from next door .
Oh , yeah . Hi .
It 's David , right ?
Yes , it 's David .
Just wanted to say hi .
Nice to ... nice to meet you , Steven .
Figured , you know ...
gonna be neighbors , you might as well be neighborly , right ?
Right .
Uh ... well , you 're gonna have to excuse us , Steven .
We have a busy day
ahead of us . Honey , come on .
Emily ...
let 's go .
Bye .
Listen , you need anything ,
just give a shout , will you ?
Okay . Thank you . See you around .
David ?
Yeah ?
You 're very lucky to have such a beautiful daughter .
Thank you .
( door opens )
You remember what I told you
about not talking to strangers ?
He 's not a stranger .
What do you mean ?
He 's our neighbor .
As far as I 'm concerned , he 's a stranger , honey .
Don 't walk away when I 'm talking to you .
I 'm telling you something .
I 'm sorry , Daddy . Weren 't you finished ?
No , I wasn 't finished .
What I 'm saying is , it 's very important
for you to listen when I tell you something .
Okay .
Okay ?
( clicking )
( thump )
( child laughing )
( kettle whistling )
( splashing , sizzling )
( whistling subsides )
What are you doing , sweetheart ?
Nothing .
What 's so funny ?
Is Charlie here ?
He just left .
Where 'd he go ?
Did you open that ?
I thought you did .
( latch squeaking )
I want to talk to Charlie .
What would you like to talk about ?
I 'd like to talk to him about all sorts of things .
Like what ?
Like , uh ... well , what makes him happy ...
what makes him sad ...
So , what do you say ?
You think you can introduce us ?
I don 't think that 's going to work .
Why 's that ?
He doesn 't like you very much .
Oh , why doesn 't he like me very much ?
Does it have something to do with Mommy ?
Honey ?
What does he tell you ?
( thunder rumbling )
( jazz playing faintly through headphones )
EMILY ( voice-over , whispering ) : ... three , one thousand ,
four , one thousand ,
five , one thousand ,
six , one thousand ,
seven , one thousand ,
eight , one thousand ,
nine , one thousand ,
ten , one thousand .
Ready or not , here I come .
( very faint , indistinct whispering )
( thunder rumbling )
( singsongy ) : Charlie ...
Charlie ...
( creaking )
Come out , come out wherever you are .
( squeak )
( gentle clinking )
( soft squeaking )
( very faint whispering )
( whispering grows louder )
( sudden click )
Charlie ?
Is that you ?
( Emily screams )
Emily !
( screaming )
( screaming continues )
Emily !
Where are you ?
What happened ?
Why are you down here ?
Emily , talk to me .
He was hiding .
Who was hiding ?
In the dark .
( loud clank )
Can I go to bed now ?
( bird screeching in distance )
( doorbell rings )
Hi .
Do you have a minute ?
Yeah . Oh , sure . Come on in .
Thank you . Thank you .
I wanted to apologize
for my husband .
He said he had a ... awkward moment
yesterday with you and Emily .
That 's all right . Don 't worry about it .
He 's harmless , really . He wouldn 't hurt a fly .
That 's fine .
It 's just that ...
we lost a child recently ... a girl ...
and in some ways , Emily reminds us of her .
I see .
He was just ... reaching out . Hmm ?
There is nothing worse in this world than losing a child .
( engine stops )
( music playing softly )
( sizzling )
Here , taste this .
I think it may be too salty .
Oh . Okay .
( slurps )
- Not bad . - Really ?
- Not bad . - Oh , good .
Really good .
Wow ! You look so pretty .
You didn 't have to get all dressed up for me .
Honey , would you go upstairs
and change into something else , please ?
Don 't you like it ?
Not for dinner , no .
Why not ?
You know why .
She looks so pretty . Let 's just eat .
I think you look really beautiful .
Did Daddy tell you that my mommy died ?
Yes , he did .
And I 'm very sorry .
Did he tell you how she died ?
Honey , I don 't think Elizabeth really wants to hear
how that happened , okay ?
She killed herself in our bathtub .
- Emily ... - Slit her wrists with a razor .
( firmly ) : Emily .
That 's enough .
Emily , I brought you something .
Your dad asked me to bring over
some of Amy 's books .
These were some of my favorites
when I was your age .
DAVID : Oh , that 's great .
Give you a chance to see what the other kids are reading
before you get started .
You gonna say thanks ?
Emily ...
( book thuds )
Emily ... Emily , stop it . That 's enough .
Do you like her , Daddy ?
- Stop this . - Charlie says you do .
- Go to your room . - He says you like her
- as much as Mommy . - Go to your room . To your room .
If you 're going to behave this way , go to your room .
Let 's hope you don 't wind up like her .
( sighing gently )
I 'm sorry .
Who 's Charlie ?
Oh , he 's her imaginary friend .
Her only friend .
( door slams )
I always wanted her to have a better childhood than I had .
Now look .
DAVID : Drive safely .
( water running )
( purring )
( wind whistles )
( indistinct conversation fading in )
MAN : Attention , please !
( thud echoing )
Maybe after a few more martinis ...
( woman laughing )
( sudden shriek )
( water dripping )
( dripping continues )
( door creaks )
( light switch clicks )
( chain rattling )
( yells )
( gasping )
Charlie did it .
You do believe me , don 't you , Daddy ?
Why are you looking at me like that ?
( panting )
( rattling )
Mr. Callaway .
I didn 't mean to disturb you .
Thought you might be needing these .
( rattling )
Those are the keys for the , uh ,
different rooms in the house .
I forgot to give them to you earlier .
I apologize .
It 's a little late to be delivering keys , isn 't it ?
Well , I thought I could slip them under the door .
Wife and I are going
to Canada first thing in the morning .
We 've got a little cabin tucked away in the woods .
Good place to clear the mind .
Everything all right ?
Well , enjoy .
What 's for breakfast ?
Honey , why would Charlie do such a horrible thing ?
Is it because of Elizabeth ?
Charlie needs to understand something , honey .
Elizabeth is not trying to take Mommy 's place .
Does he understand that ?
Honey , I can 't help you
if you don 't talk to me .
Why doesn 't he like Elizabeth ?
Because she likes you .
And ?
He doesn 't want you to be happy .
Honey ...
you know this has nothing to do with Charlie .
You do know that .
It 's about you , honey .
And that 's okay .
Charlie doesn 't exist .
You shouldn 't say that .
Why not ?
You 're going to make him mad .
Oh , well , so what ?
I 'll get him mad .
Let him come out and yell at me . Good .
I want to see him . Where is he ?
You want to see him ?
Who 's that supposed to be ?
Charlie and Mommy .
She would have liked him .
No , trust me , honey .
Mommy wouldn 't like Charlie .
That 's not what he says .
What do you mean ?
What do you mean ? What does he say ?
What does he say ?
What does Charlie say ?
Talk to me . What does he say ?
He says he would have satisfied her .
Who told you to say that ?
Charlie did .
No , who ... who told you that ?
There is no Charlie . Who said it ?
Charlie did !
He did not . Who said it ?
( singsongy ) : Charlie ! Charlie !
Charlie ! Charlie !
( giggling )
Hey ...
( laughing )
Hey , sweetheart .
I 'm so happy you came .
It 's so good to see you .
Want to show me the house ?
Yeah .
Okay .
Hey , David . How are you ?
Good . Good to see you .
Good to see you , too .
Glad you could come .
KATHERINE : Do you like it here ?
I 'm having a lot of fun .
You are ?
Tell me about your friend Charlie .
He doesn 't like me to talk about him .
I 'm sure he wouldn 't mind if you told me .
( music box playing " Mockingbird " quietly )
Tell me , what do you guys do together ?
Play games .
What kind of games ?
Hide and seek .
That 's our favorite .
Sounds like Charlie 's a lot of fun .
( music box continues playing )
So what do you guys talk about ?
I don 't know .
Bunch of things .
Sometimes he even talks about you .
Really .
And what does he say ?
You can tell me .
He 's afraid you 're going to get in the way .
In the ... In the way of what ?
Our game .
What game is that ?
Upsetting Daddy .
Isn 't she pretty ?
KATHERINE : David , I 'd like to bring Emily back with me .
At least for a little while , so she can be evaluated .
I 'm just worried bringing her back will make her worse .
She 's not well .
I know that .
And she 's not your patient .
I know that , too .
She thinks it 's a game .
She 's using Charlie to get to you .
I know things
haven 't gone as well as we hoped , but ...
do you really think bringing her back to New York
is going to make that much of a difference ?
It 's worth a try .
All right , look .
I 'll give it two more weeks ,
and if there 's no improvement , I 'll bring her back .
( Emily humming " Mockingbird " )
( water running )
( door creaks softly )
What are you doing , Daddy ?
Nothing .
What were you looking at ?
No , I was just getting ready to tuck you in .
Good night .
Daddy ?
Yeah , sweetheart ?
Can you close the door ?
You don 't want the light ?
I don 't need it anymore .
Okay .
( shoe drops on floor )
( inaudible )
Hi .
Hello . David .
I thought I 'd return the favor .
Oh , thank you .
( inhales )
Mmm ! Apple !
My favorite !
You can make yourself at home .
I 'll be back in a second .
Thank you .
( floorboard creaking )
You must think we 're pretty crazy
keeping all these toys around .
It 's , um ...
It 's hard to find the right place for them , you know ?
( sobbing ) : I 'm sorry .
No , you have nothing to be sorry about .
It 's just , I ...
I 've had no one to talk to .
You know that I am a psychologist .
I 've dealt with many people
in similar circumstances ,
and if you and your husband
would like to talk about this , it might help .
He 's ... been having ...
a tough time this past couple of weeks .
In-In ... wh-what sense ?
You have no idea how painful it can be .
How painful
he can make it .
I 'm sorry .
I 've already said too much .
Please , I can ...
Listen to me . Please , I can help you .
No , he 'll be back any moment .
You just talk to me . I can help you .
No .
You have to go .
Wha ?
( hail pattering loudly )
( doorbell chimes )
( music plays faintly over headphones )
Hello ?
David ?
Emily ?
( floorboard creaking )
Hello ?
David ?
Emily ?
( knocking )
Emily , are you in here ?
Didn 't you hear me calling ?
Daddy 's not here .
Well , actually , it was you that I came to see .
Would you mind if we talked for a moment ?
I brought you some daisies .
I wasn 't sure which one was your favorite color ,
so I just ... got all kinds .
Thanks .
Emily , I 'm really sorry
about what happened the other night .
I want you to know that I 'm not trying
to come between you and your dad .
Do you think maybe we could start over ?
We could be friends ?
Do you like games ?
I love games .
Would you like to play one ?
I 'm already playing .
What game are you playing ?
Hide and seek .
Don 't you need another person to play that game ?
He 's hiding .
Who 's hiding ?
Charlie .
Charlie 's hiding .
Where 's he hiding ?
You stay here .
( singsongy ) : Charlie ...
Come out , come out , wherever you are ...
- ( fierce growl ) - ( screams )
No !
( gasps )
( playful yet sinister music playing )
Emily ?
Em ?
( cartoon music builds dramatically )
( explosion on TV )
( turns TV off )
( knocks twice )
Emily ?
What are you doing ?
What are you drawing , honey ?
( rattling )
( wind whooshing )
What happened ?
( firmly ) : Emily ,
what happened ?
( doorbell rings )
( screen door squeaks )
Oh , hello , Sheriff .
( soles scraping on mat )
Mind if I come in for a minute ?
( screen door closes )
( door closes )
HAFFERTY : Afraid I have some bad news .
There 's been an accident .
I found Elizabeth Young 's car crashed on the side of the road .
Is she okay ?
I don 't know .
She wasn 't inside .
I spoke to her niece Amy .
Uh-huh .
She told me she came up here to see you .
You seen her ?
No , I haven 't seen her .
No .
Would you mind ...
I had a glass of water ?
Sure , uh ...
Just want , uh ,
- water , uh ? - Yeah .
Sure .
At first , I thought
she might have crashed on the way up .
But taking a second look .
I seen the tire tracks leading down the hill .
So , she must have at least stopped by .
Well , maybe she forgot something ,
or turned around , or
I don 't know , but , uh ...
Maybe , uh ... Maybe Emily 's seen her .
No , that couldn 't be .
Emily was here upstairs .
Could you call her ?
Sure . I ...
I can call her , yeah .
I can ask her .
Emily ...
Emily ?
Em ?
Honey ...
Come on down . Come on .
Hello , Emily .
Emily , you know Elizabeth Young ?
You seen her come by in the last few hours ?
If I stepped away for a minute ,
you sure there 's nothing you 'd want to tell your daddy ?
I 'm sure .
Good girl .
You can go on up to your room and play .
Cute kid .
Thank you .
If you hear anything , you 'll give me a call ?
I will , Sheriff .
I will , and you can do the same .
I want to check around the neighborhood .
You and Emily gonna be here ?
We 'll be here .
Just making sure .
Thanks for the water .
You 're welcome .
Emily ?
( panting )
- ( sobbing ) - Emily ,
where is she ?
Where is Elizabeth ?
( dinging )
( sobbing )
( sniffling )
( screaming )
Oh , God .
What did you do ?
- I didn 't do anything ! - Who did it ?
- Who did it , then ? - Charlie .
- Don 't say Charlie . - I 'm telling you ...
( Emily sobbing )
What is going on ?
Charlie .
Who is Charlie ? Where is he ?
Just , please , help me understand what 's happening here .
I can 't . I can 't .
Help me !
( whispers ) : I can 't .
( panting )
Did you have a part in this ?
He made me help him .
He made me ...
( sniffles )
He made me .
This is him ? Is this Charlie ?
I can 't tell you .
Who is this ? !
Please , I can 't .
I 'm sorry .
( panting )
You stay right here .
- Don 't move . - Oh , please don 't leave me .
Do not move . You stay right here .
EMILY : You can 't stop him , Daddy !
( panting )
( rattling )
( clunking )
( door clatters )
( doorknob rattling )
( clanking , rattling )
( rattling )
( door creaking )
Hello ?
KATHERINE : Emily ?
Emily , what 's happening ?
I don 't want to play with Charlie anymore .
Emily , where 's your father ?
Daddy can 't save me now .
Emily ?
( door opening )
Emily , sweetie , are you there ?
- Are you okay ? - ( footsteps approaching )
( panting )
( water dripping )
He just left .
( wind whistling )
Where is he ?
EMILY : He 's hiding !
Where are you ? !
( dog barking in distance )
You .
You . What are you doing here ?
I heard some noises . I saw you come out
of the woods with a shovel . Everything all right ?
No .
Emily all right ?
You stay away .
I want to see her .
You stay away . I 'm gonna call the cops .
I want to see her now .
You sick fuck .
- I want to see her . - Uh , stay away .
( grunts )
( David panting )
( panting )
( screaming )
( lively cartoon music plays on TV )
( coughs )
( panting )
EMILY : Daddy ?
Honey ... stay upstairs .
Stay upstairs .
Upstairs .
( lively music continues on TV )
( wind whistling )
You stay away !
You get out of here !
( David panting )
It 's okay , sweetheart .
Charlie 's gone .
- He 'll come back . - No .
( sobbing ) : I know he will .
No , he 's gone . He 's gone .
Please don 't make me see Charlie , Daddy .
Please don 't make me see Charlie .
I 'm so sorry I didn 't believe you .
I 'm so sorry , honey .
Please don 't leave me again .
Please don 't leave me again . Not again .
( creaking in distance )
( wind howling )
( cartoon music continues )
( creaking )
Please don 't make me see Charlie .
( porch light squeaking in wind )
( squeaking continues )
( wood creaking )
( wind whistling )
( squeaking continues )
DAVID : Is Charlie here right now ?
( whistling )
I think he 's sleeping .
( wind whistling )
( elevator bell echoes )
( dance music playing )
MAN ( in distance ) : Come out , come out ,
wherever you are .
( sultry laughter )
( passionate sighs , moaning )
( laughs )
( moaning )
( muffled shouts )
( screams )
( porch light squeaking in wind )
Can you see now , Daddy ?
( squeaking continues in distance )
It 's okay .
( sniffling quietly )
Daddy 's gone now .
( cartoon music plays softly )
( insistent knocking on door )
HAFFERTY : Dr. Callaway ?
( knocking continues )
Anybody home ?
( indistinct radio communication )
( woman screams on TV , cartoon music plays )
( door opens )
HAFFERTY : Hello ?
( footsteps approaching )
( footsteps ascending stairs )
Hello ?
( scratching on paper )
Emily ? Hey ...
where 's your dad ?
Neighbor called .
Said there was a problem .
Everything all right ?
( sniffles )
What you drawing there ?
You . Dying .
Emily ?
( light switch clicks )
( stairs creaking )
DAVID : Marco ...
Hello ?
( loud creaking )
( light footsteps running in distance )
( rattling )
Dr. Callaway ?
DAVID : Marco ...
( door creaking )
( clicking switches )
( sighs )
( panting )
Polo .
( body squeaking on floor )
( body dragging )
( door creaking )
( creaking )
( sniffling )
( sniffles )
( spoon clatters on floor )
( panting )
I can 't help but sense a certain tension between us .
What 's the matter ? Don 't you want to play anymore ?
Don 't you want to have fun ?
( sniffles )
Hmm ?
You want your daddy back ? Is that it ?
You like him more than me , don 't you ?
( quietly ) : No .
Oh , oh , liar .
( quietly ) : I 'm not .
( chanting ) : Liar , liar ...
You 're a big fat liar .
You killed Mommy .
( wind whistling )
One , one thousand ...
Two , one thousand ...
Three , one thousand ...
Four , one thousand ...
Five , one thousand ...
Hello ?
( quiet , slow footsteps )
( soft rattling )
( wind whistling faintly )
( gasps )
( panting )
Oh , God , David , you scared me .
David ?
( gasps )
( groaning )
( grunting )
( screaming )
That 's funny .
I could 've sworn I saw a little girl
by the name of Emily come in here .
Emily .
I wonder ...
where she could be .
Could she be hiding under the bed ?
( chuckles ) : No ...
Could she be hiding under this bed ?
No .
( chuckles )
Could she be ...
hiding in the closet ?
( panting )
( screams )
# Papa 's gonna buy you #
# A mockingbird #
# And if that mockingbird don 't ... sing #
# Papa 's going to buy you a diamond ring #
# And if that diamond ring turns brass #
# Papa 's going to buy you a ... looking glass #
# And if that looking glass gets broke #
# Papa 's going to buy you ... a billy goat . #
( panting )
( singing )
( rattling door )
Emily ?
( banging )
( panting )
( gasps )
Emily , open up for Daddy .
( loud banging on door )
( panting )
( window frame creaking )
( grunting )
Mommy misses you .
( Emily sobbing )
( panting )
( gasps )
Emily ?
( panting )
DAVID ( distant ) : Emily !
Emily !
( panting )
Emily ... your daddy 's looking for you .
( water splashing )
( David humming )
# Papa 's gonna buy you ... #
( water splashing )
( playing " Mockingbird " )
( rattling )
( music box continues to play )
( panting )
( music continues )
DAVID : Katherine .
( Katherine gasps )
( panting ) : Charlie ?
No , it 's-it 's me . It 's David .
Where is Emily ?
Katherine , I ...
- Emily ! - It 's all right .
I just want to explain to you what it is ...
- Stay right there . - You were right .
- Emily ! - You were right .
I never should 've brought her up here .
It was a mistake .
I mean , Emily 's not
the person who 's ... not well .
It 's me .
And you said it ...
" Trauma causes pain , " and you were right .
We 're going to get you some help , okay ?
I 'm sorry .
( grunts )
( groaning )
( screams )
( gagging )
EMILY : Dad !
( Katherine gagging )
( coughing , gasping )
DAVID : There you are .
Don 't ...
What ?
( whimpering ) : Don 't hurt her .
Why ?
She 's my friend .
I thought I was your friend .
Please , Charlie .
( David humming )
( sobbing )
( cocks gun )
Hide and seek .
- ( two gunshots ) - ( Emily screams )
( sobbing )
( " Mockingbird " continues playing )
KATHERINE : It 's okay . It 's okay .
You 're safe now .
Time for school , sweetheart .
Okay .
Have you got your homework ?
Yes .
Did you brush your teeth ?
Great .
( laughs )
( haunting melody begins )
# # CHILD ( vocalizing )
# # CHILD ( singing )
# # ( singing ends )
( orchestra continues theme )
Ripped by SkyFury